George TZORTZOPOULOS

Taking part in the creation of innovative and fun games, using modern technologies and gadgets, I offer 7+ years of professional experience, my skills and passion for quality games to a demanding and fastpaced environment with an eve on detail and aesthetics.

Key Skills and Knowledge

Experience

Krafton - Vector North

Senior Gameplay Programmer

Ianuary 2024 - Present

Project Gold Rush - Development of modular gameplay systems for an online action-adventure sandbox game, bouncing between rapid prototyping and deep refactoring.

Tech: UE5, C++ • Platforms: PC

Tasks: Gameplay features (quests, weather, mining, resources, moving levels, props, events, progression, wanted system et al.), multiplayer optimizations, prototyping, bug fixing

> 505 Games - DR Studios

Gameplay Programmer

May 2021 - November 2023

Hawken Reborn – Gameplay programmer and owner of gameplay related systems for an online, live-service game, while managing the Gameplay code team. Designed, prototyped and worked on a variety of gameplay systems and features.

• **Tech:** UE4, C++, Playfab/Azure

• Platforms: PC

• **Tasks:** Gameplay features (e.g. 3Cs, abilities, weak spots, missions, unit/prop spawning/management, difficulty scaling, resources, economy), physics, multiplayer optimizations, VFX/SFX, tools, plugins, UI, task management, mentoring, code reviews, planning, prototyping, bug fixing

Climax Studios

Programmer

Jun 2020 – May 2021

EA Sports PGA Tour – Generalist programmer in various domains including gameplay, rendering and platform specific optimizations.

• **Tech:** Frostbite Engine, C++

Platforms: PC, PS4, PS5, XB1, XBSX

Tasks: Profiling, optimizations, bug fixing

Personal Info

Nationality: Greek

<mark> Age:</mark> 34

Address: Orfeos 12

Palaio Faliro 17564, Greece

Phone:

+30 6942991517

@ Email:

george.tzortzopoulos@gmail.com

Portfolio:

www.gtzortzopoulos.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ge orge-tzortzopoulos/

Destruction AllStars – Accessibility work for a multiplayer arena game with vehicular combat.

Tech: UE4, C++Platforms: PS5

• Tasks: Input, UI, rendering, settings, bug fixing

> Nacon - Kylotonn

Gameplay Programmer

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019

Test Drive Unlimited – Porting a vehicular game from an external proprietary engine to the in-house one.

• Tech: KT Engine, External Engine, C++

• **Platforms:** PC, PS5, XBSX

• **Tasks:** Porting a massive codebase

WRC 8 – Gameplay programmer for the official game of the WRC championship.

Tech: KT Engine, C++Platforms: PC, PS4, XB1

• **Tasks:** Gameplay features (e.g. crew management, quests, dynamic weather), UI, rendering, tools, bug

fixing

> Okénite Animation

Developer

Feb 2018 - Sep 2018

Worked on various real-time rendered applications.

• **Tech:** UE4, C++, Unity, C#

• **Platforms:** PC, VR/AR, Mobile

• **Tasks:** feature development, R&D, UI, rendering, shaders, model creation/optimization/integration

> Fremen Corp

Developer (Intern)

Jun 2017 - Dec 2017

Worked on various mobile and web serious games and gamified applications.

• **Tech:** Unity, C#, Python, JavaScript/HTML/CSS, iQuery

• Platforms: Mobile, Web

• **Tasks:** Gameplay features, full-stack development, client/server communication, bug fixing, QA

(refer to the portfolio for more projects and information)

Education

University of Piraeus (Greece) – Bachelor in Informatics *Software Engineering and Intelligent Systems*

University of Castilla-La Mancha (Spain) Erasmus in Informatics

Languages:

Greek (native), English (proficient), French (intermediate), Spanish (intermediate)

Interests

Gaming – I spend a lot of my free time playing both casual and competitive games of various game genres, while I also tend to be up-to-date in relation to gaming news and share them with the people around me.

Music – I play various musical instruments, with drums being the one that passionates me the most, I have had various releases and live performances.

Cartoons – I love cartoons; animated movies/series but most of all Japanese anime.